Finding Aid for the Allegra Fuller Snyder papers, 1960-2010 LSC.1881
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Research Materials and Organizations Files., 1960-2010
  - UCLA Course Material-Dance 226 Dance Ethnology., 1967-1978 (Box 101, Folder 9)
    Course description, bibliographies, handouts. "Levels of Event Patterns: Defined in terms of time and space."
  - UCLA Course Material-Dance 226 Dance Ethnology Early Notes., 1965-1976 (Box 101, Folder 10)
    Notes and materials used for the development of the program Dance Ethnology. Course description, bibliographies, handouts.
  - UCLA Course Material-Dance 240 Production Arts Seminar., 1988 (Box 101, Folder 11)
    Course proposal and description.
  - UCLA Course Material-Dance 249 Dance in Visual Media., 1990-1993 (Box 101, Folder 12)
    Course syllabus. Brochures for dance on film and television.
  - UCLA Course Material-Dance 249 Dance in Visual Media Readings (1 of 2)., various (Box 102, Folder 1)
    Photocopies of 23 articles.
  - UCLA Course Material-Dance 249 Dance in Visual Media Readings (2 of 2)., various (Box 102, Folder 2)
    Photocopies of 14 articles.
  - UCLA Course Material-Dance 251 Movement Therapy., 1965-1970s (Box 102, Folder 3)
    Course syllabus, bibliographies. Two letters to Dr. Lessa in which AFS discusses her concerns with the approach of the courses in regards to dance and anthropology.
  - UCLA Course Material-Dance 280 Advanced Studies in Dance Ethnology (1 of 2)., 1972-1988 (Box 102, Folder 4)
    Course syllabus, handouts, bibliographies. "A Clarification of My Approach to Study, Teaching and working in the Field of Dance Ethnology with Thanks to Alan Merriam."
  - UCLA Course Material-Dance 280 Advanced Studies in Dance Ethnology (2 of 2)., 1968-1976 (Box 102, Folder 5)
    "The Collecting of Dances" handout. Handwritten notes.
  - UCLA Course Material-Dance 298 Special Studies in Dance Ethnology., 1980s (Box 102, Folder 6)
    Course description. Preparation for field observation, culminating in the field trip to the Yaqui Easter ceremony in Tucson, Arizona.
  - UCLA Course Material-Dance 441 Production Practicum., 1988 (Box 102, Folder 7)
    Brief course outline.
  - UCLA Course Material-Dance 460 Dance Ethnology Seminar., 1987-1990 (Box 102, Folder 8)
    Course syllabus for "Seminar in Dance Ethnology Research, Fieldwork, and the Thesis."
  - UCLA Course Material-Dance 490 Projects in Choreography and Performance., 1988 (Box 102, Folder 9)
  - UCLA Course Material-Dance 498 Professional Internship., 1988 (Box 102, Folder 10)
  - UCLA Course Material-Dance 596 Theoretical Studies in Dance, PhD of 298., 1986 (Box 103, Folder 1)
    Course description. Notes on course discussion.
  - UCLA Course Material-Ethnic Arts 190 Senior Colloquium., 1977-1982 (Box 103, Folder 2)
    Course descriptions, handouts, bibliographies. Body Ritual Among the Nacirema" by Horace Miner. see also Boxes 43 Ethnic Arts and 48 WAC.
  - UCLA Course Material-Ethnic Arts 190 Senior Colloquium Readings., various (Box 103, Folder 3)
    Bound and photocopied course readings.
  - UCLA Course Material-Extension 1960s., 1967-1969 (Box 103, Folder 4)
    Fall 1967, spring and fall 1968, spring 1969 University Extension "Liberal Arts Discussion and Lecture-Discussion." Course descriptions. Film receipts.
  - University of Surrey., 1982-1996 (Box 103, Folder 5)
    Brochures. Correspondence about AFS Honorary Visiting Professor of Dance Studies at University of Surrey.
  - Van Tuyl, Marian., 1985-1988 (Box 103, Folder 6)
    AFS appraisal of van Tuyl film collection. A 50 year chronology of her professional life. Descriptions of her films.
  - Visual Anthropology Course Descriptions., 1976 (Box 103, Folder 7)
    Samples of course descriptions taught by others.
  - West Coast Dance., 1974 (Box 103, Folder 8)
    Vol. 1 no. 2, Vol. 1 no. 3, Vol. 1 no. 4 of "West Coast Dance!"
  - World Affairs Conference., 1986-1990 (Box 103, Folder 9)
    Program, participant's directory, and discussion guide for the 1987 40th annual "Conference on World Affairs." AFS presentation about Buckminster Fuller "Where His Ideas Came From."
  - World Dance Alliance., 1991 (Box 104, Folder 1)
    Jan. and Aug. "The Americas Summary Report."
  - World Synergy Institute., 1985 (Box 104, Folder 2)
    Letter and flyer for "What is Buckminster Fuller's World Game?: An informal introduction, with Buckminster Fuller on film."
  - Writings-AFS 1940s., 1949 (Box 104, Folder 3)
    Excerpts from "Movement and Communication."
  - Writings-AFS 1960s (1 of 6)., 1965, 1969 (Box 104, Folder 4)
    Sept. 1965 "Dance Magazine" AFS article "Three Kinds of Film" pages have been removed. April 1969 "Dance Magazine" with directory of 16mm dance films co- compiled and co-annotated by AFS. Loose-leaf extra copies of AFS article "Films, Who Can Make Them How Can We Use Them? A report on today's expanding dance film scene."
  - Writings-AFS 1960s (2 of 6)., 1967-1969 (Box 104, Folder 5)
    AFS article "The Kinesthetic Environment" from "Impulse Annual of Contemporary Dance 1967" edited by Marian van Tuyl. AFS article "On Film-A new dimension" from "Focus on Dance V." AFS article "Films that Show How Children Learn by Dancing" from "Film News." AFS article "Sources of Film on Dance" from JOHPER.
  - Writings-AFS 1960s (3 of 6)., 1968 (Box 104, Folder 6)
    NEA report by consultant AFS "The Relationship of Film to Dance: A report and analysis of problems, needs, possibilities and potentials in this area."
  - Writings-AFS 1960s (4 of 6)., 1962-1965 (Box 104, Folder 7)
    "Thoughts on the Documentary Dance Film: What is it? Do we have it? Do we need it?" "Some Aspects of the Nature of the Rhythmic Experience and Its Possible Therapeutic Value." "Excerpts from a Letter to Bella Lewitzky." Hopi article.
  - Writings-AFS 1960s (5 of 6)., 1966-1967 (Box 104, Folder 8)
    UCLA Committee on Fine Arts "Dance / Film" and the accompanying "The Playgoer." AFS article about cine-dance from "Dance Perspectives 30."
  - Writings-AFS 1960s (6 of 6)., 1966-1967 (Box 105, Folder 1)
    Film review of Kashia Pomo Indians in Sept. 1967 "Ethnomusicology." "Isadora-In a New Perspective."
  - Writings-AFS 1970s (1 of 3)., 1972-1979 (Box 105, Folder 2)
    "Dance and Film as Kinesthetic Experience." Statement prepared April 17, 1975 about the role of dance within a university setting. "Levels of Event Patterns: An attempt to place dance in a holistic context." "Film as a Means of Holistic Communication." NEH sponsored "Support Materials for Use by Teachers and Students Viewing Baroque Dance 1675-1725, a Film."
  - Writings-AFS 1970s (2 of 3)., 1972 (Box 105, Folder 3)
    "The Dance Symbol." "The Media for Research and Publication in Dance."
  - Writings-AFS 1970s (3 of 3)., 1972-1973 (Box 105, Folder 4)
    "Dance Films: A study of choreo-cinema." 1972 ADTA monographs "Some Aspects of the Nature of the Rhythmic Experience and Its Possible Therapeutic Value."
  - Writings-AFS 1980s (1 of 2)., 1985-1989 (Box 105, Folder 5)
    1989 ADTA reprint "Some Aspects of the Nature of the Rhythmic Experience and Its Possible Therapeutic Value." "Response to Tourism and Who the People Are: Cultural conservatism in tourist art and dance." "Danced in My Head: Thoughts on dance as a way of knowing." "Cosmology, Dance and Transformation." "Transformation, Inner Space and the Future of Dance." "Celebration: Un monde d'art et de rituel."
  - Writings-AFS 1980s (2 of 2)., 1980-1984 (Box 106, Folder 1)
    "Shamanism, the Primacy of Imagery (Cross-Cultural Perspective)." Remarks at the Laban Bartenieff Institute of Movement Studies. Proposal statement for "A Cross-Cultural Ethnohistoric Study Linking Shamanism to Aspects of European and New World Performance Events Including Carnivals, Festivals and Ritual." Script for "Celebration: A world of art and dance." "Education and the Student in Dance Ethnology." NYU class presentations. Unpublished presentations.
  - Writings-AFS 1990s., 1990, 1992 (Box 106, Folder 2)
    "A World Dance Organization and Its Importance to Furthering Research: A summary." "The Dance Symbol: a 1992 update demonstrating the potential effects of interactive laser technologies on research and publishing strategies."
  - Writings-AFS undated. (Box 106, Folder 3)
    "Shamanism: A reassessment for dance ethnologists." "Some Contributions of Gertrude Prokosch Kurath to Dance Ethnology." Note cards for speech.
  - Writings-AFS Compilation copy 1., 1967-1985 (Box 106, Folder 4)
    "A Compilation of the Writings of Allegra Fuller Snyder."
  - Writings-AFS Compilation copy 2., 1967-1985 (Box 106, Folder 5)
  - Writings-Focus on Dance Materials., 1964 (Box 106, Folder 6)
    Arts and Humanities Institute "Dance for the American Male" brochure, director Miriam Gray. Correspondence. "The Scene on Film: A new dimension."
  - Writings-Kinesthetic Environment Materials., 1967 (Box 106, Folder 7)
    Correspondence with Mariam van Tuyl. "The Kinesthetic Environment."
  - Yaqui-Arts Genesis, Sue Pfaffl., 1989-1992 (Box 107, Folder 1)
    Correspondence. Project Choki third annual benefit featuring R. Carlos Nakai. 1991 article "A Couple's Life Work" about adobe house of Rosamond and Edward Spicer. "Project Tachiria" by Arts Genesis and San Ignacio Yaqui Council. See also Box 2 folder 3.
  - Yaqui-Chapayekas and Pascola., 1981 (Box 107, Folder 2)
    AFS notes for presentation "Chapayekas and Pascola Contrast and Consistencies: Two dimensions of the Yaqui Easter."
  - Yaqui-Correspondence., 1976-1990 (Box 107, Folder 3)
    Correspondence about the trips to Arizona for the Yaqui ceremonies.
  - Yaqui-Huichol, Tarahumara., 1925-1991 (Box 107, Folder 4)
    Photocopies of 1925 "Yaqui Indian Dances of Tucson, Arizona," 1934 "The Sacred Clowns of the Pueblo and Mayo-Yaqui Indians," 1946 "The Yaqui Easter Play of Guadalupe, Arizona," Wilder's "The Yaqui Deer Dance: A study in cultural change," Spicer's 1956 "Social Structure and the Acculturation Process," Furst's "An Indian Journey to Life's Source." Reprint for Furst's "Myth in Art: A Huichol depicts his reality." 1964 booklet by Tom Bahti "Southwestern Indian Arts & Crafts."
  - Yaqui-Lenten Easter Ceremony., 1980-1991 (Box 107, Folder 5)
    Mini-cassette "Yaqui Lecture." Two editions of "A Yaqui Easter" by Muriel Thayer Painter. Project Yaqui brochure. Yoemem Tekia Foundation Pascua Pueblo events brochure. "Pascua Pueblo Giotojame." "A Yaqui Pahtorela." AFS article "Levels of Event Patterns: A theoretical model applied to the Yaqui Easter ceremonies." Newsclippings.
  - Yaqui-Notes., undated (Box 107, Folder 6)
    A few handwritten notes.
  - Yaqui-Research Material., 1980-1991 (Box 107, Folder 7)
    Newsclippings. "Yaqui Women: Contemporary life histories" brochure. Bibliographies for Yaqui research. Photocopies of "Seyewailo the Flower World Yaqui Deer Songs," Kolaz's "Yaqui Pascola Masks," 1936 "The Yaqui Indian Dances," and some color illustrations of Yaqui dancers. Yaqui historical timeline.
  - Yaqui-Trip., 1979-1991 (Box 107, Folder 8)
    Schedules, directions, maps for the annual dance department trip to view the Yaqui Easter ceremonies curated by AFS.